<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">33438773</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2021</Year>
            <Month>01</Month>
            <Day>13</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1460-2075</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2021</Year>
                        <Month>Jan</Month>
                        <Day>13</Day>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>The EMBO journal</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>EMBO J</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>ZSP-1 is a Z granule surface protein required for Z granule fluidity and germline immortality in Caenorhabditis elegans.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>e105612</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.15252/embj.2020105612</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>Germ granules are biomolecular condensates that form in germ cells of all/most animals, where they regulate mRNA expression to promote germ cell function and totipotency. In the adult Caenorhabditis elegans germ cell, these granules are composed of at least four distinct sub-compartments, one of which is the Z granule. To better understand the role of the Z granule in germ cell biology, we conducted a genetic screen for genes specifically required for Z granule assembly or morphology. Here, we show that zsp-1, which encodes a low-complexity/polyampholyte-domain protein, is required for Z granule homeostasis. ZSP-1 localizes to the outer surface of Z granules. In the absence of ZSP-1, Z granules swell to an abnormal size, fail to segregate with germline blastomeres during development, and lose their liquid-like character. Finally, ZSP-1 promotes piRNA- and siRNA-directed gene regulation and germline immortality. Our data suggest that Z granules coordinate small RNA-based gene regulation to promote germ cell function and that ZSP-1 helps/is need to maintain Z granule morphology and liquidity.</AbstractText>
                <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Wan</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Gang</ForeName>
                    <Initials>G</Initials>
                    <Identifier Source="ORCID">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-5990-7438</Identifier>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>MOE Key Laboratory of Gene Function and Regulation, State Key Laboratory of Biocontrol, School of Life Sciences, Sun Yat-sen University, GuangZhou, GuangDong, China.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Genetics, Blavatnik Institute, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Bajaj</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Lakshya</ForeName>
                    <Initials>L</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Genetics, Blavatnik Institute, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Fields</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Brandon</ForeName>
                    <Initials>B</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Genetics, Blavatnik Institute, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Biological Engineering, Synthetic Biology Center, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Dodson</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Anne E</ForeName>
                    <Initials>AE</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Genetics, Blavatnik Institute, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Pagano</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Daniel</ForeName>
                    <Initials>D</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Genetics, Blavatnik Institute, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Fei</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Yuhan</ForeName>
                    <Initials>Y</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Genetics, Blavatnik Institute, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>College of Agriculture, Nanjing Agricultural University, Nanjing, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Kennedy</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Scott</ForeName>
                    <Initials>S</Initials>
                    <Identifier Source="ORCID">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-7974-8155</Identifier>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Genetics, Blavatnik Institute, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <DataBankList CompleteYN="Y">
                <DataBank>
                    <DataBankName>GEO</DataBankName>
                    <AccessionNumberList>
                        <AccessionNumber>GSE150960</AccessionNumber>
                    </AccessionNumberList>
                </DataBank>
            </DataBankList>
            <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Grant>
                    <GrantID>32070798</GrantID>
                    <Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency>
                    <Country/>
                </Grant>
                <Grant>
                    <GrantID>2019A1515110744</GrantID>
                    <Agency>Basic and Applied Basic Research Foundation of GuangDong</Agency>
                    <Country/>
                </Grant>
                <Grant>
                    <GrantID>DRG-2304-17</GrantID>
                    <Acronym>DRCRF</Acronym>
                    <Agency>Damon Runyon Cancer Research Foundation</Agency>
                    <Country>United States</Country>
                </Grant>
                <Grant>
                    <GrantID>1F32GM125345-01</GrantID>
                    <Agency>Ruth L. Kirschstein National Research Service Award</Agency>
                    <Country/>
                </Grant>
                <Grant>
                    <GrantID>GM088289</GrantID>
                    <Agency>HHS | National Institutes of Health (NIH)</Agency>
                    <Country/>
                </Grant>
                <Grant>
                    <GrantID>GM132286</GrantID>
                    <Agency>HHS | National Institutes of Health (NIH)</Agency>
                    <Country/>
                </Grant>
            </GrantList>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2021</Year>
                <Month>01</Month>
                <Day>13</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>England</Country>
            <MedlineTA>EMBO J</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>8208664</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0261-4189</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gene regulation</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">germ granules</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">germline immortality</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">molecular condensates</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">small RNA</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2020</Year>
                <Month>05</Month>
                <Day>14</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
                <Year>2020</Year>
                <Month>12</Month>
                <Day>02</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2020</Year>
                <Month>12</Month>
                <Day>14</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2021</Year>
                <Month>1</Month>
                <Day>13</Day>
                <Hour>8</Hour>
                <Minute>38</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2021</Year>
                <Month>1</Month>
                <Day>14</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2021</Year>
                <Month>1</Month>
                <Day>14</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33438773</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15252/embj.2020105612</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
        <ReferenceList>
            <Title>References</Title>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Arribere JA, Bell RT, Fu BXH, Artiles KL, Hartman PS, Fire AZ (2014) Efficient marker-free recovery of custom genetic modifications with CRISPR/Cas9 in Caenorhabditis elegans. Genetics 198: 837-846</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Audas TE, Audas DE, Jacob MD, David Ho JJ, Khacho M, Miling Wang J, Perera K, Gardiner C, Bennett CA, Head T et al (2016) Adaptation to stressors by systemic protein amyloidogenesis. Dev Cell 39: 155-168</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Bagijn MP, Goldstein LD, Sapetschnig A, Weick E-M, Bouasker S, Lehrbach NJ, Simard MJ, Miska EA (2012) Function, targets, and evolution of Caenorhabditis elegans piRNAs. Science 337: 574-578</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Batista PJ, Graham Ruby J, Claycomb JM, Chiang R, Fahlgren N, Kasschau KD, Chaves DA, Weifeng Gu, Vasale JJ, Duan S et al (2008) PRG-1 and 21U-RNAs interact to form the piRNA complex required for fertility in C. elegans. Mol Cell 31: 67-78</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Beshore EL, McEwen TJ, Jud MC, Marshall JK, Schisa JA, Bennett KL (2011) C. elegans dicer interacts with the P-granule component GLH-1 and both regulate germline RNPs. Dev Biol 350: 370-381</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Billi AC, Fischer SEJ, Kim JK (2018) Endogenous RNAi pathways in C. elegans. WormBook 1-49. https://doi.org/10.1895/wormbook.1.170.1</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Boke E, Ruer M, Wühr M, Coughlin M, Lemaitre R, Gygi SP, Alberti S, Drechsel D, Hyman AA, Mitchison TJ (2016) Amyloid-like self-assembly of a cellular compartment. Cell 166: 637-650</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Brangwynne CP, Eckmann CR, Courson DS, Rybarska A, Hoege C, Gharakhani J, Jülicher F, Hyman AA (2009) Germline P granules are liquid droplets that localize by controlled dissolution/condensation. Science 324: 1729-1732</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Brenner S (1974) The genetics of Caenorhabditis elegans. Genetics 77: 71-94</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Buckley BA, Burkhart KB, Sam Guoping Gu, Spracklin G, Kershner A, Fritz H, Kimble J, Fire A, Kennedy S (2012) A nuclear argonaute promotes multigenerational epigenetic inheritance and germline immortality. Nature 489: 447-451</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Campbell AC, Updike DL (2015) CSR-1 and P Granules suppress sperm-specific transcription in the C. elegans germline. Development 142: 1745-1755</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Claycomb JM, Batista PJ, Pang KM, Weifeng Gu, Vasale JJ, van Wolfswinkel JC, Chaves DA, Shirayama M, Mitani S, Ketting RF et al (2009) The argonaute CSR-1 and Its 22G-RNA cofactors are required for holocentric chromosome segregation. Cell 139: 123-134</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Costantini LM, Fossati M, Francolini M, Snapp EL (2012) Assessing the tendency of fluorescent proteins to oligomerize under physiologic conditions. Traffic 13: 643-649</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Courchaine EM, Alice Lu, Neugebauer KM (2016) Droplet organelles? EMBO J 35: 1603-1612</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Das PP, Bagijn MP, Goldstein LD, Woolford JR, Lehrbach NJ, Sapetschnig A, Buhecha HR, Gilchrist MJ, Howe KL, Stark R et al (2008) Piwi and piRNAs act upstream of an endogenous siRNA pathway to suppress Tc3 transposon mobility in the Caenorhabditis elegans germline. Mol Cell 31: 79-90</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Dodson AE, Kennedy S (2019) Germ granules coordinate RNA-based epigenetic inheritance pathways. Dev Cell 50: 704-715.</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Eddy EM (1975) Germ plasm and the differentiation of the germ cell line. Int Rev Cytol 43: 229-280</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Fire A, Xu S, Montgomery MK, Kostas SA, Driver SE, Mello CC (1998) Potent and specific genetic interference by double-stranded RNA in Caenorhabditis elegans. Nature 391: 806-811</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Gent JI, Schvarzstein M, Villeneuve AM, Sam Guoping Gu, Jantsch V, Fire AZ, Baudrimont A (2009) A Caenorhabditis elegans RNA-directed RNA polymerase in sperm development and endogenous RNA interference. Genetics 183: 1297-1314</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Gu W, Shirayama M, Jr DC, Vasale J, Batista PJ, Claycomb JM, Moresco JJ, Youngman EM, Keys J, Stoltz MJ et al (2009) Distinct argonaute-mediated 22G-RNA pathways direct genome surveillance in the C. elegans germline. Mol Cell 36: 231-244</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Guang S, Bochner AF, Pavelec DM, Burkhart KB, Harding S, Lachowiec J, Kennedy S (2008) An argonaute transports siRNAs from the cytoplasm to the nucleus. Science 321: 537-541</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Hubstenberger A, Noble SL, Cameron C, Evans TC (2013) Translation repressors, an RNA helicase, and developmental cues control RNP phase transitions during early development. Dev Cell 27: 161-173</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Ishidate T, Ozturk AR, Durning DJ, Sharma R, Shen E-Z, Chen H, Seth M, Shirayama M, Mello CC (2018) ZNFX-1 functions within perinuclear nuage to balance epigenetic signals. Mol Cell 70: 639-49</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Jain S, Wheeler JR, Walters RW, Agrawal A, Barsic A, Parker R (2016) ATPase-modulated stress granules contain a diverse proteome and substructure. Cell 164: 487-498</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Kawasaki I, Shim YH, Kirchner J, Kaminker J, Wood WB, Strome S (1998) PGL-1, a predicted RNA-binding component of germ granules, is essential for fertility in C. elegans. Cell 94: 635-645</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Knutson A, Egelhofer T, Rechtsteiner A, Strome S (2017) Germ granules prevent accumulation of somatic transcripts in the adult Caenorhabditis elegans germline. Genetics 206: 163-178</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Kroschwald S, Maharana S, Mateju D, Malinovska L, Nüske E, Poser I, Richter D, Alberti S (2015) Promiscuous interactions and protein disaggregases determine the material state of stress-inducible RNP granules. Elife 4: e06807</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Laos T, Cabral G, Dammermann A (2015) Isotropic incorporation of SPD-5 underlies centrosome assembly in C. elegans. Curr Biol 25: R648-R649</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Lee H-C, Weifeng Gu, Shirayama M, Youngman E, Jr DC, Mello CC (2012) C. elegans piRNAs mediate the genome-wide surveillance of germline transcripts. Cell 150: 78-87</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Lev I, Toker IA, Mor Y, Nitzan A, Weintraub G, Antonova O, Bhonkar O, Shushan IB, Seroussi U, Claycomb JM et al (2019) Germ granules govern small RNA inheritance. Curr Biol 29: 2880-91</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Lin R (2003) A gain-of-function mutation in Oma-1, a C. elegans gene required for oocyte maturation, results in delayed degradation of maternal proteins and embryonic lethality. Dev Biol 258: 226-239</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Lin Y, Protter DSW, Rosen MK, Parker R (2015) Formation and maturation of phase-separated liquid droplets by RNA-binding proteins. Mol Cell 60: 208-219</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Little SC, Sinsimer KS, Lee JJ, Wieschaus EF, Gavis ER (2015) Independent and coordinate trafficking of single Drosophila germ plasm mRNAs. Nat Cell Biol 17: 558-568</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Manage KI, Rogers AK, Wallis DC, Uebel CJ, Anderson DC, Nguyen DAH, Arca K, Brown KC, Cordeiro Rodrigues RJ, de Albuquerque BFM et al (2020) A tudor domain protein, SIMR-1, promotes siRNA production at piRNA-targeted mRNAs in C. elegans. Elife 9: e56731</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Molliex A, Temirov J, Lee J, Coughlin M, Kanagaraj AP, Kim HJ, Mittag T, Paul Taylor J (2015) Phase separation by low complexity domains promotes stress granule assembly and drives pathological fibrillization. Cell 163: 123-133</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Niepielko MG, Eagle WVI, Gavis ER (2018) Stochastic seeding coupled with mRNA self-recruitment generates heterogeneous drosophila germ granules. Curr Biol 28: 1872-81</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Ouyang JPT, Folkmann A, Bernard L, Lee C-Y, Seroussi U, Charlesworth AG, Claycomb JM, Seydoux G (2019) P granules protect RNA interference genes from silencing by piRNAs. Dev Cell 50: 716-28</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Patel A, Lee HO, Jawerth L, Maharana S, Jahnel M, Hein MY, Stoynov S, Mahamid J, Saha S, Franzmann TM et al (2015) A liquid-to-solid phase transition of the ALS protein FUS accelerated by disease mutation. Cell 162: 1066-1077</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Phillips CM, Montgomery TA, Breen PC, Ruvkun G (2012) MUT-16 promotes formation of perinuclear mutator foci required for RNA silencing in the C. elegans Germline. Genes Dev 26: 1433-1444</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Pitt JN, Schisa JA, Priess JR (2000) P granules in the germ cells of Caenorhabditis elegans adults are associated with clusters of nuclear pores and contain RNA. Dev Biol 219: 315-333</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Placentino M, de Jesus Domingues AM, Schreier J, Dietz S, Hellmann S, de Albuquerque BFM, Butter F, Ketting RF. (2020) Intrinsically disordered protein PID-2 modulates Z granules and is required for heritable piRNA-induced silencing in the Caenorhabditis elegans embryo. EMBO J https://doi.org/10.15252/embj.2020105280</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Putnam A, Cassani M, Smith J, Seydoux G (2019) A gel phase promotes condensation of liquid P granules in Caenorhabditis elegans embryos. Nat Struct Mol Biol 26: 220-226</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Sakaguchi A, Sarkies P, Simon M, Doebley A-L, Goldstein LD, Hedges A, Ikegami K, Alvares SM, Yang L, LaRocque JR et al (2014) Caenorhabditis elegans RSD-2 and RSD-6 promote germ cell immortality by maintaining small interfering RNA populations. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 111: E4323-E4331</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Seydoux G, Fire A (1994) Soma-germline asymmetry in the distributions of embryonic RNAs in Caenorhabditis elegans. Development 120: 2823-2834</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Sheth U, Pitt J, Dennis S, Priess JR (2010) Perinuclear P granules are the principal sites of mRNA export in adult C. elegans germ cells. Development 137: 1305-1314</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Shukla A, Yan J, Pagano D, Dodson A, Yuhan F, Gorham J, Seidman J, Wickens M, Kennedy S (2020) poly(UG)-tailed RNAs in genome protection and epigenetic inheritance. Nature 582: 283-288</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Simon M, Sarkies P, Ikegami K, Doebley AL (2014) Reduced insulin/IGF-1 signaling restores germ cell immortality to Caenorhabditis elegans piwi mutants. Cell Rep 7: 762-773</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Spike CA, Bader J, Reinke V, Strome S (2008) DEPS-1 promotes P-granule assembly and RNA interference in C. elegans germ cells. Development 135: 983-993</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Spracklin G, Fields B, Wan G, Becker D, Wallig A, Shukla A, Kennedy S (2017) The RNAi Inheritance Machinery of Caenorhabditis elegans. Genetics 206: 1403-1416</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Strome S, Wood WB (1982) Immunofluorescence visualization of germ-line-specific cytoplasmic granules in embryos, larvae, and adults of Caenorhabditis elegans. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 79: 1558-1562</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Svendsen JM, Reed KJ, Vijayasarathy T, Montgomery BE, Tucci RM, Brown KC, Marks TN, Dieu AH, Nguyen CM, Phillips CM et al (2019) Henn-1/HEN1 promotes germline immortality in Caenorhabditis elegans. Cell Rep 29: 3187-99</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Toretsky JA, Wright PE (2014) Assemblages: functional units formed by cellular phase separation. J Cell Biol 206: 579-588</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Trcek T, Grosch M, York A, Shroff H, Lionnet T, Lehmann R (2015) Drosophila germ granules are structured and contain homotypic mRNA clusters. Nat Commun 6: 7962</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Vastenhouw NL, Brunschwig K, Okihara KL, Müller F, Tijsterman M, Plasterk RHA (2006) Gene expression: long-term gene silencing by RNAi. Nature 442: 882</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Voorhees PW (1992) Ostwald ripening of two-phase mixtures. Annu Rev Mater Sci 22: 197-215</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Voronina E, Seydoux G, Sassone-Corsi P, Nagamori I (2011) RNA granules in germ cells. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Biology 3: a002774</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Wan G, Fields BD, Spracklin G, Shukla A, Phillips CM, Kennedy S (2018) Spatiotemporal regulation of liquid-like condensates in epigenetic inheritance. Nature 557: 679-683</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Wang G, Reinke V (2008) A C. elegans piwi, PRG-1, regulates 21U-RNAs during spermatogenesis. Curr Biol 18: 861-867</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Wang JT, Smith J, Chen B-C, Schmidt H, Rasoloson D, Paix A, Lambrus BG, Calidas D, Betzig E, Seydoux G (2014) Regulation of RNA granule dynamics by phosphorylation of serine-rich, intrinsically disordered proteins in C. elegans. Elife 3: e04591</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Weber SC, Brangwynne CP (2012) Getting RNA and protein in phase. Cell 149: 1188-1191</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Westphal V, Rizzoli SO, Lauterbach MA, Kamin D, Jahn R, Hell SW (2008) Video-rate far-field optical nanoscopy dissects synaptic vesicle movement. Science 320: 246-249</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Woodruff JB, Gomes BF, Widlund PO, Mahamid J, Honigmann A, Hyman AA (2017) The centrosome is a selective condensate that nucleates microtubules by concentrating tubulin. Cell 169: 1066-77</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Woodruff JB, Hyman AA, Boke E (2018) Organization and function of non-dynamic biomolecular condensates. Trends Biochem Sci 43: 81-94</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Wylie C (2000) Germ cells. Curr Opin Genet Dev 10: 410-413</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Xu F, Feng X, Chen X, Weng C, Yan Qi, Ting Xu, Hong M, Guang S (2018) A cytoplasmic argonaute protein promotes the inheritance of RNAi. Cell Rep 23: 2482-2494</Citation>
            </Reference>
            <Reference>
                <Citation>Yigit E, Batista PJ, Bei Y, Pang KM, Chen C-C, Tolia NH, Joshua-Tor L, Mitani S, Simard MJ, Mello CC (2006) Analysis of the C. elegans argonaute family reveals that distinct argonautes act sequentially during RNAi. Cell 127: 747-757</Citation>
            </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

</PubmedArticleSet>